Matija Osrečki

Front End Software Engineer

♥ Zagreb, Croatia

hello@matijao.com

in linkedin.com/in/matijao

github.com/matijaoe

Experience

Front End Developer @ Four of them LLC

August 2022 - Present // Zaprešić, Croatia // Remote

- Implemented core functionality for the ground-up platform reconstruction using Nuxt 3
- · Shipped interactive web components used in hundreds of pharmacy sites across Germany
- · Led the development of the custom component library leveraging Vue, UnoCSS & Storybook
- · Mentored colleagues and regularly provided constructive feedback on code improvements
- · Played a crucial role in defining the project's architecture, providing well-thought-out insights during vital decision-making phases

Junior Front End Developer @ Three of them Ltd.

August 2021 - July 2022 // Zaprešić, Croatia // Remote

- Maintained and improved the performance of the flagship IhreApotheken.de platform
- · Proactively identified areas for improvement and tackled technical debt
- Developed and shipped an inventory tracking app for pharmacy suppliers using Vue,
- · Led the development of the custom component library leveraging Vue, UnoCSS & Storybook
- Developed and maintained internal NPM packages built in TypeScript

Junior Full Stack Developer @ Infokarta d.o.o.

May 2021 - July 2021 // Split, Croatia // Remote

- Collaborated with a small team to develop a geographic information system (GIS) based web application for several local governments in the Dalmatian Region
- Used Nuxt, Vue, Vuex, Sass, Bootstrap, Mapbox, Node, Express, PostgreSQL

Projects

Fare @ TVZ

August 2022 - January 2023

Application for tracking personal finances and attaining financial independence.

- · Developed as a college final-year project
- Built with Nuxt 3, Vue, TypeScript, TanStack Query, UnoCSS, Prisma, PlanetScale

github.com/matijaoe/fare

Qwiz @ TVZ Mc2 2022

February 2022 - June 2022

Platform for creation, organization & discovery of pub quizzes.

- Developed as a part of the TVZ Mc2 student programming competition
- Lead our team of three, designed the user interface, built most of the front-end, built out API endpoints and modeled the SQL database
- Built with Next, Nest, TypeScript, Mantine UI, React Query, Prisma, PlanetScale, NX

app.qwiz.party github.com/qwiz-app/qwiz

Aimo @ TVZ Mc2 2021

March 2021 - June 2021

Social media platform connecting ambitious individuals with accountability partners.

- Developed as a part of the TVZ Mc2 student programming competition
- · Won the First place and the Best design award
- Managed the team, designed the user interface and built most of the client-side
- Built with Nuxt, Vue, Tailwind CSS and Google Firebase

About

Self-motivated front-end oriented software engineer, driven by a never-ending curiosity and a competitive drive to deliver exceptional user experiences.

Deeply passionate about quality producst, UI/ UX design, open-source, developer experience, clean code and bitcoin.

Skills

Programming Languages

TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL,

Libraries & Frameworks

Vue, Nuxt, React, Svelte, Tailwind CSS, UnoCSS, Node, Bun, Prisma, TanStack Query

Tools & Platforms

Git, Vite, Storybook, pnpm, GitHub, GitLab

Front End Development, UI/UX Design, Bitcoin

Education

Zagreb University of Applied Sciences

TVZ // 2019 - 2023 // Zagreb, Croatia Bachelor of Computer Software Engineering

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing

FER // 2018 - 2019 // Zagreb, Croatia Computer Science

Awards and honors

- First place at TVZ Mc2 2021
- Best design award at TVZ Mc2 2021
- STEM scolarship

Interests

Bitcoin, Economics, Literature, Psychology, Design, Cycling